<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Wind Power</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Wind Power</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">ckkirk24@tamu.edu</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="menu_home">Home</string>
    <string name="menu_design">Turbine Orientations</string>
    <string name="menu_histogram">Charge Data</string>
    <string name="menu_settings">Set Max Charge</string>

    <string name="hawt_vawt_comparison">
    <![CDATA[
    <b>Comparison between HAWT and VAWT:</b><br><br>
    <ol>
        <li><b>HAWT (Horizontal Axis Wind Turbine):</b>
        <br>
        - <i>Design:</i> HAWTs have a horizontal axis, similar to a traditional windmill.
        <br>
        - <i>Orientation:</i> HAWTs are oriented to face into the wind.
        <br>
        - <i>Efficiency:</i> HAWTs are known for their high efficiency and power output.
        </li><br>
        <li><b>VAWT (Vertical Axis Wind Turbine):</b>
        <br>
        - <i>Design:</i> VAWTs have a vertical axis and often have a unique, egg-beater or helical design.
        <br>
        - <i>Orientation:</i> VAWTs can capture wind from any direction without turning.
        <br>
        - <i>Efficiency:</i> VAWTs are generally less efficient than HAWTs and are used for smaller-scale applications.
        </li>
    </ol>
    <br>

    <b>Ideal Use Cases:</b><br><br>
    HAWTs are ideal for large-scale wind farms and commercial electricity generation due to their higher efficiency and power output. They perform well in areas with consistent and strong wind patterns.<br>
    VAWTs, on the other hand, are suitable for smaller-scale applications and can be used in urban or residential settings where wind patterns may vary. Their ability to capture wind from any direction makes them adaptable in changing conditions.

    <br><br>
    <b>Why HAWTs are generally more efficient:</b><br><br>
    HAWTs have a design that allows them to take advantage of higher wind speeds, especially at higher altitudes. Their orientation directly into the wind optimizes energy capture. Additionally, HAWTs are well-suited for larger blades, resulting in higher torque and power generation. These factors contribute to their higher efficiency compared to VAWTs.

    <br><br>
    Click <a href="https://www.windturbinestar.com/hawt-vs-vawt.html">here</a> to navigate to a website with more information on the different turbine orientations.
    ]]>
</string>




</resources>